Jai Hind friends.  Many people have the question
that which company's insurance should they
take?  If you are taking any insurance, be it life
insurance or any type of
term insurance, if you are
taking any insurance, then from which company should you
take it?  How to know if this company is
genuine or not.  Is
it working as per the government guidelines or not?  Or
many people also want to know
in which bank to open an account?  Be it a savings
account or a current account.  In which bank
should it be opened?  Who to trust?
Because since a few years ago you must have seen
that a few years ago many companies which
were chit fund companies ran away with so much money from the people that the
people who had kept money in it became
completely bankrupt.
Along with this, the Sahara case also happened in 2012 and since then the
money is still stuck in it.
People have lost their trust as they have not received their money.
What is it that people are
unable to understand this thing?  Are you confused as to
where to keep your money now?  Where to
invest?  Which company should I keep
?  In which bank should it be kept or should it be
invested in insurance.  Let me
tell you that if you do a little research and gather
information about it, then
you can invest your money in the right place.
Whether you are getting insurance or
keeping it in the bank after opening a proper account and
getting insurance, this is also very
easy in today's date.  In today's date everything is
online.  You can search everything online.  You
can get information about it.  You
can get all its data from Google.  You can get the details.  But
still I am telling you that the
RD that you do is
called recurring deposit.  Like you used to keep money in Sahara
or you used to keep money in a chit fund company.
Many people say that we have a
savings account in the bank and we
deposit Rs 10,000, Rs 20,000, Rs
5,000 in it once.  If needed, we take it out again.
But in Sahara, we used to keep Rs.
2000, 4000 or 300
or 500 every month and once in a year or 2
years or 5 years, we used to do maturity and
some work was done with that money.   There was a
savings account but it could do some
work.  So such accounts are
opened in every bank also.  So let me tell you that
whatever
bank is working under RBI, let me tell you it is
SBI.  It became Punjab National Bank, it
became Bank of Boudha, it became Indian Bank, it became
Union Bank of India, it became Canara Bank.
All these government banks are big banks.   Apart from this,
go to the private sector.   It is
ICICI Bank, it is HDFC Bank, it is
Axis Bank, it is Indusind Bank, it is
Kotak Mahindra Bank.  There are many
private banks which are good banks,
big banks, all of them work on the rules and regulations of RBI.
And these are all strong
banks, you can open an account in all these banks
or you will definitely have an account.  And as far as
savings are concerned, those who save every month.
RD is opened in all these banks.  Very few people
know this.  If you don't know, then know that
RD is opened.  You will go there and
say that in whichever bank you have an account, be it
government or private,
you will
go there and say that you want to open an RD.
They will say Recurring Deposit RD, they will open that RD for
you and what will they do?  It will
link it to your account.  Whatever
account there is, be it current account, savings
account or Jan Dhan account, it will be linked to it.
Now what happens is that you have to
deposit money into that account every month.  You don't
even have to go to deposit it.  You are
running a shop, a small shop,
a business or doing some work.
You know I have to save this much in a month.
So if you want to deposit Rs 500 in your account every month, then if
you have opened a bank account of Rs 5000 then Rs 1000, if you have
opened a bank account of Rs 5000 then the amount of Rs 5000 that you have deposited in
your account every month should be there in your account every
month.  So what will happen is that
that much money will be automatically deducted from your account every month.
He will go into RD and you will
not even know about it.  It will be cut and gone.
You will get his account number.  Now
what happens is that when the maturity happens, whether you have taken a loan for one year,
two years or five years
, on that day whenever the
maturity happens,
that money along with full interest will again come to your account.  There is no need to
fill any form for maturity, nor
do anything else.  So see how easy it is.  It
is neither risky like Sahara nor
risky like a chit fund company, there is no fear of running away,
no fear of drowning, nothing.  Your money is being
saved comfortably.  You are using the
money on the saving order which you know is my 2000
5000 10000 20000 5000.  On
this
pretext, that money is being deposited in you for two, four, five years.  The
money with which you have
nothing to do and for which you have taken it for two, three years, four years, five years, you
get some money in return.  That gets your work done
or you take a sum of money and then
invest it somewhere.  So this is how money is
made from money.  So, RD can be opened
in any bank which is a trusted bank,
so you can do it there.  You do
not need to keep money in the chit fund.   There is
no need to keep money in a company like Sahara anywhere.  You
can take RD in the same bank in which you have an account.
Now let's come to insurance.  Which
company should I get insurance from?  Insurance:
Any company that comes under the guidelines of IRBD can provide
insurance in any sector.  Sara has the same
condition.  Same in all is your
safety.  There are about 24
insurance companies in our country and
all are working under IRDA.  Whether you are
taking LIC.  LIC is also a government company.
Apart from this, let me tell you that HDFC also has
insurance.  Birla Sun Life
Insurance.  Bajaj
is the insurance of aliens.  Shri Ram
is insured.  Many banks have
insurance from many companies.  Apart from this, if I
talk about SBI, SBI also has life
insurance.  So you can take it from any company.
Everything is fine.  But
you should take insurance directly from any big company.
Insurance from any big company which is
trustworthy.  Look at his ranking.
Get information about him,
check his track record in Google to know
what is his claim settlement?  How much is it?  What
is the percentage?  Only then did I get insurance from that company.   In
such a situation, I urge people to take
insurance only in LIC.  Even if you
feel that the returns are a little less or
many people complain that
this is that, but here there is confidence that
your money will not sink because the 24 companies
that I am talking about are insurance companies,
all of them together do
not have as much capital as LIC alone has,
so LIC
can never sink in life due to its sinking.  What is the second one?   There is
no need for the government to think about this.  Now let me give
you one more option.
Apart from these two, the best option
right now for the common man and the poor
people is the post office. Go to the post office and you
can open any
type of account there. There is 100% guarantee of trust there
because it works directly under the government. So,
you
can also take insurance in the post office and open an account
and you will get all the plans of RD FD in the post office. So, this is the
best option in the present times. If you do not
want to go to the bank, do
not want to go to the insurance company and are looking for a very easy and simple
way, then
go to the post office and get it done.  This is also a best option.
So let me tell you that in today's date, if any
agent of any company brings a new company
, makes some kind of offer,
tempts you to give more money, then you should
not get involved in all those things.  This
is a better option.  You get a little less money, but it is the
best.  Yours remains safe.
Apart from this, if you have any question in your mind, want to
ask something, want to know something, or
for other options, then you
can write in the comment box.  I will definitely make a video on your topic also.
Many people keep asking such
questions.  So in answer to the question
I am making this video.  If your question
comes, I will definitely make a video on your questions too. If you are
not a subscriber then subscribe to the
channel.  If you are already a subscriber, I am
grateful for that.  See you
in the next video with a new topic.
Thanks for now.  Thank you.  Jai Hind.